Meytal Mitchell Vainstub

UX Research | Digital Anthropology

Contact

46 Grundy street, London, UK E14 6DR

(+44) 07729046656

meyvain@gmail.com Portfolio Linkedin

Languages

Summary

I'm a junior human-centred user experience researcher.

Passionately advocating user's voice.

Identifying opportunities for growth by uncovering user needs, process and context of use for better user engagement journeys.

Good design isn't based on assumptions, it's based on real-world data.

Education

2018–2019 **MSc** Digital Anthropology

Graduated with Merit.

As a user research student I focused on phenomena such as therapy robots, AI impact on health care, Mobile-Health apps and more.

Thesis Embodying Interaction: ethnographic exploration of surgeons performing robotic assisted surgery

Preformed user-centred Human-Robot-Interaction research in the case study of surgical robots, including ethnographic study in surgery rooms and interviews with surgeons working with the Da Vinci MIS robot.

Modules Bio-Medical anthropology, Design anthropology, Data in Digital culture

2017 winter **Fellowship** International Centre for the Study of Radicalisation King's College Fellowship dedicated for researching the Israeli and Palestinian conflict.

2013–2016 **BA** Sociology, Anthropology & Theatre The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Israel Graduated with honours

Thesis Coders Adaptation

Exploring processes of knowledge sharing and practices adaptations of volunteer coders at The Public Knowledge Workshop.

Modules Sociology of entrepreneurship and innovation, Global Organizations

Functional Experience

2013-Now Research & Analysis

University Work

As a masters graduate with strong analytical skills and critical thinking, I have experience with both qualitative and quantitative research methods, with special expertise in ethnographic data collection and analysis.

- Practical Presentation Approach: In order to unpack research in a digital sphere, I presented my research findings on biohackers culture in a conceptual website and an Augmented Reality (AR) app that I've developed.
- Direct Impact Oriented: For my undergrad dissertation, I underwent a six month research project on volunteer coders working towards government transparency. Using my ethnographic data and analysis I was able to help on their volunteer adapting practices, making an impact on their own goals.
- Clear & Engaging Presentation: As Junior Journalist, publishing articles in my university journals, I've learned that clarity is essential, bringing your findings and ideas quickly to be engaged and understood.
- *Motivated Learner:* Independently enrolled on accredited online modules, MOOCs, from Goldsmith University of London and the University of Michigan, enhancing my own abilities to better assist professional projects.

University College London

- Project Planning and Realising: I founded the Hebrew University of Jerusalem women's volley-ball team. As a captain, I led the team to second place in the National League. I met regularly with university committees and other stakeholders, including the National Volleyball Association, organising budget meetings, managing team schedule, and coordinating competitions.
- Creative Initiative: As a Junior Radio Producer & Broadcaster with "Kol Israel" national Israeli radio station, I brought ideas to the editorial table. Gaining experience with initiating, researching and designing interviews based segments to be broadcast on air.
- Self-Starter: Created a theatre blog and discovered by Itzik Giuli, the Israeli Theatre Festival Art Director, who supported me in becoming the official student blogger of the festival.

Work Experience

2018 spring	Research Assistant Assisting in a qualitative research on cross-cultural Hi-Tech corporations.	Ben-Gurion University, Israel work relations in the case study of global
2017–2019	Bartender Welcome to try my fabulous espresso martini I can fix	The Crown, London up like no one else ;]
2014–2016	Telemarketing Shift Manager Responsible for integrating new employees, coordinating sales targets for a team of 7-11 telemarketing agents in a fast-paced sales environment and monitoring sales on a daily basis.	
2009–2011	Field Medic Being the first life support in the field, training and base	Air Force Medical Corps, Israel Defence Forces se clinic.

Awards

2014	Dean's Excellence Award	Hebrew University of Jerusalem
	Awarded for academic achievements by the Social Scientific Scientific Awarded for academic achievements by the Social Scientific Sci	ences faculty.
2010	Commendation for Outstanding Performance	Air Force Medical Corps, Israel Defence Forces
	Awarded a commendation for devoted work and organisational innovative.	

Voluntary Activities

2012	Orphanage Nanny	Hogar De Gina orphanage, Chusica, Peru.	
	'Hogar De Gina' was disconnected from the	world. After living with the girls I launched a website	
	for the orphanage. Enabling worldwide exposure and volunteering opportunities to this day.		
2008	Nurse Assistant	Women's Health Department, Rambam Hospital, Haifa, Israel	
	Joined nurses on daily routine patient care and helped running the department as needed.		

References

Manish Chand MD
Director of Advanced MIS Surgery Programme
University College London Hospital
250 Euston Road,
London, UK
NW1 2BU

m.chand@ucl.ac.uk

Ludovic Coupaye

Anthropology of Technology Research
University College London
Gower Street,
London, UK
WC1E 6BT
I.coupaye@ucl.ac.uk
+44 (0)20 7679 8642